<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"><channel><title>斯科特·H·杨</title><atom:link href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><link/> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/<description>学得更快，成就更多</description><lastbuilddate>2023 年 7 月 14 日星期五 16:31:32 +0000</lastbuilddate><language> en-US</language><sy:updateperiod>每小时</sy:updateperiod><sy:updatefrequency>1</sy:updatefrequency><image/><url> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/favicon.png</url><title>斯科特·H·杨</title><link/>https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/<width> 32</width><height> 32</height><item><title>读者邮袋：范围、学习方式、促智药以及学习你注定要忘记的东西的价值</title><link/>https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/07/12/reader-mailbag-range-learning-styles-nootropics/<comments> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/07/12/reader-mailbag-range-learning-styles-nootropics/#respond</comments><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Young]]></dc:creator><pubDate> Thu, 13 Jul 2023 05:47:39 +0000</pubDate><category><![CDATA[General]]></category><guid ispermalink="false"> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/?p=15238 </guid><description><![CDATA[<p>我回答读者有关《范围》一书、学习方式、促智药等的问题！</p><p> <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/07/12/reader-mailbag-range-learning-styles-nootropics/">读者邮袋：范围、学习方式、促智药和学习你注定要忘记的东西的价值</a>首先出现在<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a>上。</p> ]]>; </description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>上周，我向时事通讯的订阅者发出了询问问题的电话。我收到了很多好的回复，所以我决定将我的回复分成两个单独的帖子。</p><p>有些问题经过了轻微编辑，我合并了一些人问的类似问题。与读者聊天总是很有趣——希望我们能把它变成一个常规功能！ </p><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="512" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Reader-mailbag-1024x512.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-14028" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Reader-mailbag-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Reader-mailbag-300x150.jpg 300w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Reader-mailbag-768x384.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Reader-mailbag-1536x768.jpg 1536w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Reader-mailbag.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>问：</strong>从我读过的您的著作来看，您似乎是集中、有针对性、甚至可能相当孤立（个人学习）学习的倡导者。此外，学习通常有答案的东西——基于技术数学的科目、语言等。</p><p>你读过大卫·爱泼斯坦的<a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Range-Generalists-Triumph-Specialized-World/dp/0735214506">《Range》</a>吗？</p><p>你对通过试错、实验、对过去的现有经验进行意义建构来学习有何看法，这些经验不是有针对性的，但它们恰好已经成为你的一部分（将它们构建成你自己的个人专长）？</p><p> <cite>-吉姆</cite></p></blockquote><p>《范围》对我来说是一本有趣的书，因为在某些方面，我就是这本书的缩影。我学到了很多不相关的东西，也做了很多随机的自我探索。我写一篇关于学习的博客，部分原因是我太善变，无法坚持任何一件事并完全掌握它。</p><p>也就是说，我认为我们需要牢记教育和认知心理学中的一些广泛的实证研究结果：</p><ol><li><strong>学生<a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1207/s15326985ep4102_1">往往会在更有指导和结构化的课程中学得更好</a>。</strong>尽管非结构化、基于发现的方法很有吸引力，但与更直接的教学方法相比，它们往往表现不佳，除非你为它们做好准备。这并不意味着通过发现来学习是没有用的；而是意味着通过发现来学习是没有用的。简单地说，通过纯粹发现来学习的有效性并没有人们经常声称的证据基础。</li><li><strong>不相关技能之间的转移<a href="https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/EJ1249779.pdf">往往相当低</a>。</strong>学习大量随机事物可能会有一些好处，但考虑到在仔细控制的研究中几乎完全缺乏“远”转移，我想说举证责任在于声称转移很大的人，而不是相反。</li><li><strong>我不认为定义不明确的技能与定义明确的技能没有什么不同（我认为这就是你在将其与学习有“答案”的东西进行对比时所谈论的内容）。</strong>事实上，学习<em>的</em>很多意义在于明确定义一项技能。如果你什么都不知道，那么问题空间就会很大，并且你不确定大量的可能性。随着您了解更多，您会找到更好的方法来表示问题以及更好的方法来解决问题。</li></ol><p>我不认为成为一名多面手并学习很多东西有什么错。生活不仅仅是为了一个单一的目标而优化。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>问：</strong>您有什么建议或策略可以更有效地从您阅读的书籍中学习吗？</p><p> <cite>-伊萨姆</cite></p></blockquote><p>我认为最重要的是多读书。阅读更多可以提高您的流利程度和背景知识，从而提高您的阅读率。人们确实低估了阅读对阅读速度的提高程度。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>问：</strong>学习风格怎么样？成为“视觉学习者”等是真实存在的吗？</p><p> <cite>-芯片</cite></p></blockquote><p>可能不会。</p><p>丹尼尔·威林汉姆（Daniel Willingham）<a href="http://www.danielwillingham.com/learning-styles-faq.html">对反对“人有学习风格”这一观点的证据</a>进行了精彩的总结。要成为真正的“风格”，它应该意味着当信息以他们喜欢的方式呈现时，人们会学得更好。研究通常没有发现以这种方式定制信息可以增加学习收益。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>问：</strong>我们一次可以学到多少东西？我们应该只选择一件事并达到一定水平，然后继续学习其他东西，还是可以同时学习多种东西？它是否会使我们的大脑超载，或者它是否有能力处理如此多的新信息？</p><p> <cite>-查里莎</cite></p></blockquote><p>您绝对可以在同一时间范围内学习多种内容。大多数中小学教育都是以此为基础的。我倾向于不鼓励同时进行多个自主学习项目，因为大多数人高估了自己可以完成的任务，最终得到了几个薄弱的项目，而不是一个有效的项目。但没有任何认知原因可以阻止它。</p><p>我认为同时学习高度相似的科目会产生问题。我从未尝试过同时学习两种新语言，尽管我建议连续练习多种语言以进行维护。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>问：</strong>您是否有任何您确信可以提高注意力和生产力的补充剂？</p><p> <cite>-加雷斯</cite></p></blockquote><p>咖啡因？老实说，其实没什么。</p><p>我不相信促智药可以毫无副作用地发挥作用。为了让促智药有意义，你必须相信大脑<em>可以</em>比它实际工作得更好，但决定其性能的内部刻度盘只是设置得不理想。但为什么进化会形成这样的大脑呢？如果转动旋钮可以提高性能且没有任何负面影响，那么进化就已经做到了这一点。</p><p>我的猜测是，真正的学习/注意力增强剂要么具有明显的下行风险（例如安非他明），要么它们针对特定的缺陷/残疾，但对一般人群无效。我很高兴在这里被证明是错误的，但我首先需要看到很多好的证据。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>问：</strong>我住在魁北克，但 30 年前离开，所以我懂一些法语。为几个月后的法国之旅做准备，重新学习法语的最快方法是什么？</p><p> <cite>-哈里什</cite></p></blockquote><p>通过<a href="https://www.italki.com/dashboard">iTalki</a>预订一些辅导时间，然后再次尝试聊天。</p><p>对于再学习来说，大部分问题是流畅度和自信心不高。工作量更少，因为知识可能已经在你的头脑中了——只是不那么自动。一些课程应该可以帮助您感觉更流利，这也将有助于增强信心，而信心是说一门语言的重要组成部分。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>问：</strong>如果您必须重新参加麻省理工学院挑战赛，了解您现在对学习、生产力等科学文献的了解，您会采取哪些不同的做法，为什么？</p><p> <cite>-杰夫</cite></p></blockquote><p>我最初梦想<a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/myprojects/mit-challenge-2/">麻省理工学院的挑战</a>是“我想知道你是否能学习麻省理工学院教授的所有计算机科学课程？”然后进一步说道，“我想知道如果我只专注于考试，我个人是否可以在 12 个月内完成。”因此，它有点做作，因为目的是通过考试，而不是获得特定目的的技能。多年来我一直这么说，但如果我的最终目标是找到一份编程工作、创办一家初创公司或成为一名研究人员，那么这个项目看起来会完全不同。</p><p>就我现在所知，我认为有一些弱点可以通过不同的方法来弥补。通过对概念的良好理解，我通过了很多考试。尽管如此，我对代数/微积分的程序知识还是很薄弱，这导致我在物理课程上苦苦挣扎，需要大量数学知识来计算答案。如果我重新完成这个项目，我会进行大量的练习来提高流畅度，也许作为开始挑战本身的先决项目。</p><p>同样，当我做编程项目时，麻省理工学院的计算机科学学位对实际编程的了解很少。这是更多的理论和数学。没关系，但如果我打算在之后立即获得一份编程工作，我会花几个月的时间深入研究一种特定的语言，以确保我能够流畅地实现我所涵盖的许多想法。</p><p>总的来说，我不确定我的学习方式会有多大改变。时间限制并没有留下太多的回旋余地来以截然不同的方式做事。但如果我有学习编程或计算机科学的更广泛目标，我可以想象很多不同的方法，这些方法可能在某些目的上产生更好的结果。</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p><strong>问：</strong>为什么我喜欢阅读非小说类作品，因为大多数作品都被遗忘了？当我们知道大部分材料都会被遗忘时，为什么我们还要对高中生进行内容“期末考试”测试？</p><p> <cite>-抢</cite></p></blockquote><p>事情被遗忘了，但它们仍然常常以印象派的方式影响着我们。我经常发现我的信念已经转向一个方向，尽管我不再记得争论的确切来源。读书的部分作用是改变你对情况的直觉，而这种直觉并不总是能追溯到其来源。</p><p> _ _ _</p><p>这就是本周的内容。下周，我将解决更多问题，包括克服拖延症、我对语言学习中有争议的输入假设的想法、运动技能等等！</p><p> <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/07/12/reader-mailbag-range-learning-styles-nootropics/">读者邮袋：范围、学习方式、促智药和学习你注定要忘记的东西的价值</a>首先出现在<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a>上。</p> ]]>;</content:encoded><wfw:commentrss> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/07/12/reader-mailbag-range-learning-styles-nootropics/feed/</wfw:commentrss><slash:comments> 0</slash:comments></item><item><title>关于最佳学习方式的八个未解答的问题</title><link/>https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/06/27/unanswered-questions/<comments> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/06/27/unanswered-questions/#respond</comments><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Young]]></dc:creator><pubDate> Wed, 28 Jun 2023 03:15:02 +0000</pubDate><category><![CDATA[General]]></category><guid ispermalink="false"> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/?p=15228 </guid><description><![CDATA[<p>关于最佳学习方式的一些困惑。您认为什么效果最好？</p><p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/27/unanswered-questions/">关于最佳学习方式的“我的八个未解答的问题”</a>一文首先出现在<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a>上。</p> ]]>; </description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>我花了很多时间思考我们如何学习。</p><p>我阅读了数百本有关该主题的书籍和文章，并撰写了数十篇论文（以及一<a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/ultralearning/">本书</a>！），试图总结和综合专家的观点，以找到实现这一目标的最佳方法。但还有很多事情我不知道！</p><p>今天，我不想提供答案，而是想提出一些我仍然存在的问题。我将根据特定主题来构建每个问题，但每个问题都可能涉及影响其他技能和主题的更广泛的问题。</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading">我未解答的问题</h2><h3 class="wp-block-heading">1. 当学习历史等广泛的学科时，与新阅读相比，应该花多少时间在检索练习上？</h3><p>我之前写过有关<a href="https://www.science.org/doi/abs/10.1126/science.1199327">检索练习相对于重读</a>的价值的文章。给学生一篇文章让他们阅读，当他们练习自由回忆文章内容时，他们学到的东西比重新阅读一遍要多。</p><p>但这里的研究重点是再次重读同一篇文章。阅读不同的来源怎么样？如果您正在研究像历史这样的广泛主题，您是否通过检索活动或阅读许多其他书籍和资源学到更多信息？</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 2. 外语片先看有字幕好还是无字幕好？</h3><p>假设您正在观看一部用您正在学习的语言拍摄的电影。你还没有达到从第一次观看就可以理解发生了什么的程度。如果您要观看多次，您应该在第一次还是第二次观看时带字幕观看？</p><p>第一次观看的理由是你会理解情节，因此在第二次观看时可以更好地吸收语言。第二次查看的理由是你会更好地关注这些单词并处理它们的含义。</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 3. 您应该从努力解决具有挑战性的数学问题开始还是只是查看说明？</h3><p>这不仅仅是我的问题——这是教育研究中备受争议的领域。马努·卡普尔（Manu Kapur）<a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.3102/00346543211019105">富有成效的失败</a>实验主张首先提出难以解决的问题。相比之下，其他人关于<a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2022/01/04/cognitive-load-theory/">认知负荷理论的</a>实验主张从明确的指令开始。</p><p>当你获得专业知识时，这两种理论都支持解决问题，因为它提供了所需的实践。但问题是，初学者不太可能事先知道正确的解决方案，他们是否会从问题优先或示例优先的方法中受益更多。</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 4. 您应该通过抽认卡学习多少新语言单词？</h3><p>我非常喜欢用抽认卡学习词汇。在我的巅峰时期，我有大约 16,000 张普通话卡片，还有几千张韩语和马其顿语卡片。</p><p>通过抽认卡记住单词的中心含义比偶然接触要快得多。然而抽认卡只能教你关于单词需要了解的部分内容。你无法感觉到这个词什么时候可能出现或者它与什么词搭配，你需要练习才能在上下文中识别和使用它。</p><p>我的假设是抽认卡很有用，但只是在一定程度上有用。常见的单词很好学，一些不常见的单词也很好学。但你应该走多远呢？最常见的 100、1000 或 9000 个单词？您应该专注于单一的核心含义还是对自己进行变体测验（例如，一张表示“划分”的卡片与表示“划分”、“除法”、“分裂”等的卡片）</p><p>偶然学习一个新单词几乎总是比刻意学习要慢。尽管如此，它还有一个额外的优势，即完整的上下文，以及对上下文中其他单词的额外练习。在某些时候，“在上下文中”学习单词可能会比死记硬背更有效。问题是这个权衡点出现在哪里。</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 5. 如果您正在学习滑雪或滑雪板，如果您坚持选择轻松的斜坡并完善您的技术，或者选择您可以轻松应对的最陡的斜坡，您会学得更快吗？</h3><p>对于认知技能，人们支持从一开始就采用“正确”的方法。如果你错误地学习了数学算法，以后就很少有机会自我纠正该知识。</p><p>然而，对于身体技能似乎有不同的思想流派。一所学校会主张在继续之前完善“正确”的技术。这是一种认为马虎的技术以后很难修复的观点，因此应该在接受更困难的挑战之前掌握它。</p><p>另一所学校则认为，一旦你在智力上理解了这项技术，你就会从在困难/变化的情况下练习中获益更多，而不是试图在更简单的环境中完善它。然而，这些复杂的设置可能会引入错误，从而导致长期的麻烦。</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 6. 学习学术计算机科学对于成功的程序员有多大用处？</h3><p>自从我参加<a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/myprojects/mit-challenge-2/">麻省理工学院挑战赛</a>以来，这个问题一直萦绕在我的脑海里。一方面，数论、算法和逻辑分析等知识在编程实践中发挥作用。另一方面，谁曾在开始解决问题之前坐下来证明问题的复杂性等级？</p><p>学术理论与实践技能之间的关系问题出现在许多领域。对于学术相关性的看法多种多样，“当然，你需要学习这一点！”到，“没有人在工作中使用过这个。”</p><p>可能的答案包括：</p><ul><li>它有帮助，但主要是针对高级工作，而不是入门级工作。</li><li>它通过使实践技能“有意义”来帮助未来的学习。</li><li>它对编程没有多大帮助，但可以帮助你找到工作。</li><li>比直接学习编程效率要低。</li></ul><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 7. 通过下较慢的棋局还是较快的棋局，你的棋艺水平会提高吗？</h3><p>假设你想快速提高你的国际象棋成绩。你应该专注于较长的游戏，其中有更多的时间来思考每一步，还是更快的游戏，虽然思考的时间较少，但你最终会在玩游戏的每个小时中看到更多的棋盘位置。</p><p>我怀疑两端都有一个极端，即学习效益会崩溃。每场比赛花费一年的时间，或者每次移动花费不到一秒的时间，可能效率不高。但最佳点位于两者之间的哪里呢？</p><p>当然，虽然这个问题对国际象棋很重要，但明确回答它会说明很多其他技能，这些技能可以以不同的“速度”完成，并且在分析深度和暴露数量之间进行权衡。</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 8、如果你想画“松”的风格，是否应该先学会“紧”控制的画？</h3><p>与下棋的快慢类似，也是艺术风格培养的问题。假设你想以“宽松”或“绘画式”的方式绘画。是否应该先以更大的控制力学习，然后随着经验的积累而放松，或者从一开始就应该相对宽松地绘画？</p><p>从更大的控制开始的论点是，我们喜欢熟练、宽松的绘画风格的大部分原因是艺术家可以通过经济的动作和笔触进行大量交流。初学者做不到这一点，所以他们最好学习基础知识并随着水平的提高而放松。</p><p>可以用数学来类比：经验丰富的数学家可以简单地说出一个复杂问题的答案，而初学者则需要手动进行缓慢的计算才能得到相同的答案。我们永远不会指望仅仅喊出答案就能成为初学者获得专家知识的一种方式。</p><p>主张从宽松开始的论点是，受控绘画的技巧不同于宽松的作品。因此，从风格上来说，早期对控制的关注可能会让以后更难发展出成功的、宽松的风格。</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading">您还有哪些未解答的问题？</h2><p>这些是我的一些未解答的问题——你的呢？在学习的过程中，你还有什么不明白的地方吗？您对我提出的问题有什么看法吗？请分享您的想法！</p><p><a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/27/unanswered-questions/">关于最佳学习方式的“我的八个未解答的问题”</a>一文首先出现在<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a>上。</p> ]]>;</content:encoded><wfw:commentrss> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/06/27/unanswered-questions/feed/</wfw:commentrss><slash:comments> 0</slash:comments></item><item><title>最低限度习惯什么时候对学习有用？</title><link/> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/06/20/minimal-habits-learning/<comments> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/06/20/minimal-habits-learning/#respond</comments><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Young]]></dc:creator><pubDate> Tue, 20 Jun 2023 15:24:27 +0000</pubDate><category><![CDATA[General]]></category><guid ispermalink="false"> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/?p=15217 </guid><description><![CDATA[<p>早些时候，我批评了每天五分钟的学习方法。现在让我们看看缓慢而耐心的方法实际上可以在哪里发挥作用。</p><p>帖子《<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/20/minimal-habits-learning/">最低限度的习惯什么时候对学习有用？》</a>首次出现在<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a>上。</p> ]]>; </description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>在上周的文章中，我写到了<a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/13/too-patient/">学习中过于耐心</a>的问题。</p><p>我特别挑选了基于简单、最小习惯的学习项目，例如，每天花五分钟在 Duolingo 上学习一门语言，或者每周写一页小说。</p><p>回顾一下：</p><ul><li>虽然这种方法很流行，但它限制了您可以进行的活动类型，通常会消除最有效的练习类型。</li><li>漫长的时间框架让你很难判断自己是否取得了进步，也很难相应地调整你的方法。</li><li>最后，虽然养成简单的习惯可以成为迈向困难行为的良好垫脚石，但对许多人来说，每天五分钟的例行公事变成了目的地，而不是热身。</li></ul><p>虽然最小习惯方法存在问题，但我应该指出，密集型项目也存在问题！密集型项目很难安排，执行起来具有挑战性，并且可能缺乏足够的空间来长期保留。</p><p>最好的方法不是坚定地坚持某种特定的方式来实现目标，而是了解每种方式的优点和缺点。所以，今天我想探讨一下什么样的学习最小习惯实际上是有用的。</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading">最低限度的习惯有什么好处？</h2><p>只要你能长期坚持，最小习惯的学习方法有两个关键优势：空间和便利。</p><p>间距是指<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacing_effect">间距效应</a>，这是一个经过充分研究的现象。当我们接触信息的时间间隔较长时，我们会比在较短的时间内接触相同数量的信息时更好地保留信息。因此，在十天内看到一个词汇项目十次会比在一小时内看到它十次产生更持久的记忆。通过在很长的时间内进行学习，最小的习惯可以潜在地利用间隔效应，从而比拥挤的时间表产生更持久的记忆。</p><p>最小习惯的第二个优点是它们很方便。正如我在上一篇文章中提到的，阻止人们培养最低限度的习惯感觉很卑鄙，因为替代方案通常是什么都不做。生活忙碌，学习辛苦，有时你只有十分钟的空闲时间。<span id='easy-footnote-1-15217' class='easy-footnote-margin-adjust'></span> <span class='easy-footnote'><a href='https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/20/minimal-habits-learning/#easy-footnote-bottom-1-15217' title="当人们有&lt;em>;几种&lt;/em>;学习不同事物的最小习惯时，这一论点就被驳斥了，这表明他们可以一次只做一件事，但很难决定要关注哪件事。"><sup>1</sup></a></span></p><p>考虑到这两个优点，我认为值得研究一下什么类型的学习目标可能适合长期传播的简单、最小的习惯。</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading">最低限度的习惯什么时候应该起作用？</h2><p>根据我的最小习惯心理模型，我希望当练习活动的认知负荷较低并且可以适应较小的时间空间时，它们会起作用。</p><p><a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2022/01/04/cognitive-load-theory/">认知负荷理论</a>背后的基本思想是，信息必须穿过意识体验的狭窄瓶颈才能发生学习。复杂的主题和技能，包含许多信息，必须将它们放在一起才能理解它们，会造成很高的认知负担。这就是学习数学和物理困难的原因之一。</p><p>然而，对于一个受试者来说，认知负荷并不是恒定的！当您学习时，您的大脑会使用分块或检索线索等机制来最大程度地减少工作记忆的负担。例如，当您第一次学习阅读时，它的认知负荷非常高，因为您必须努力识别每个字母。但最终，当你自动识别单词和句子时，阅读的认知负荷会变低。</p><p>新的学习对工作记忆的要求各不相同。有些技能和概念本质上认知负荷较高，因为它们有许多新的、相互作用的部分。相比之下，其他想法本质上是相互独立的，可以一次学习一个。</p><p>考虑学习计算化学中的量子力学轨道与记住元素周期表上的质量。前者有很多信息，需要同时使用来执行计算。相反，记忆任务涉及（大部分）不相关的事实。</p><p>有鉴于此，抽认卡可能会帮助您记住周期质量，但对于学习求解微分方程以找到电子轨道来说，它们并不能很好地发挥作用。计算任务中的各种问题要求您将大量信息“加载”到短期记忆中，因此，对于除了经验最丰富的化学家之外的所有人来说，有效的练习活动看起来更像是您必须关注的问题集一段时间了。</p><p><strong>最少的习惯可能比转向新的技能领域更能保持知识和流畅性。</strong>随着时间的推移，持续、重复的练习对于提高流利度来说是理想的选择，但在存在纠正反馈的情况下进行刻意调整的效果较差。</p><p>因此，低调的日常写作习惯可能会让写作变得<em>更容易</em>，但它可能不会帮助你达到更高的熟练程度。后者可能需要刻意的练习限制，迫使您使用不会自动出现的样式或结构，并且需要一定的关注和努力（可能还需要一些外部反馈）。作为一个最低限度的习惯，这是很难或不可能维持的。</p><p>最低限度习惯的另一个限制是练习活动需要适合每天的一小部分时间并且有效。因此，例如，速降滑雪可能无法成为大多数人的最低习惯，因为它需要在雪山上进行长途旅行才能进行跑步。许多技能很难进行最低限度的练习，因为没有相关的种类练习将适合该时间范围。</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading">最小习惯可能发挥作用的一些例子</h2><p>我过去曾使用过一些极简的习惯——无论有效还是无效。上面阐述的理论阐明了我认为它们有效的地方（以及它们失败的地方）。特别是，我认为最低限度的习惯可能对以下方面很有效：</p><ul><li><strong>广泛的学科知识。</strong>每天阅读博客、YouTube 教育视频或浏览相关 Reddit 子版块不会产生专业知识。尽管如此，它仍然可以让您很好地<em>涵盖</em>主要思想，即使您需要认真练习才能熟练使用它们。</li><li><strong>抽认卡和记忆孤立的事实。</strong>那些可以被制作成原子的、独立的、可快速测试的知识的东西也是不错的候选者。我成功地利用碎片时间学习了大量的词汇，这对于维持知识也有好处。</li><li><strong>流利并保持既定技能。</strong>保持最少的努力可以帮助培养对材料的流畅性，这是最终掌握的一个重要部分。</li></ul><p>相比之下，我认为最低限度的习惯不太适合需要刻意练习的情况。学习新的、复杂的技能；或者在最低习惯要求的时间/精力限制内不可能进行有效的练习。</p><p>值得注意的是，耐心/不耐心的区别往往与实际学习时间的更大考虑相形见绌。根据<a href="https://www.languagetesting.com/how-long-does-it-take">一些合理的估计</a>，掌握一门语言可能需要 500-2000 小时的课堂时间。如果你遵循每天五分钟的方法，使用像普通话这样的“硬”语言，那意味着你还需要将近七十年才能达到这个门槛！如果你实际上没有足够的练习，即使是最有效的学习策略也无法让你达到目标。</p><p>帖子《<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/20/minimal-habits-learning/">最低限度的习惯什么时候对学习有用？》</a>首次出现在<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a>上。</p> ]]>;</content:encoded><wfw:commentrss> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/06/20/minimal-habits-learning/feed/</wfw:commentrss><slash:comments> 0</slash:comments></item><item><title>过于耐心的问题</title><link/>https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/06/13/too-病人/<comments> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/2023/06/13/too-patent/#respond</comments><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Young]]></dc:creator><pubDate> Tue, 13 Jun 2023 15:28:00 +0000</pubDate><category><![CDATA[General]]></category><guid ispermalink="false"> https://www.scothyoung.com/blog/?p=15198 </guid><description><![CDATA[<p>耐心是学习的恶习还是美德？关于最少的习惯是否足以掌握的一些思考。</p><p>帖子<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/13/too-patient/">“过于耐心的问题”</a>首先出现在<a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a>上。</p> ]]>; </description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>精通通常与耐心联系在一起。毕竟，做好一件事需要很长时间，只有长期坚持下去的人才能达到技艺的顶峰。</p><p>考虑到这种共同的联想，我发现很有趣的是，在老虎·伍德高尔夫生涯最好的几年里，他的教练<a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Pro-Lessons-Father-Claude-Harmon/dp/0307338045">布奇·哈蒙</a>听到了相反的观点：</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>那些坚持保持耐心并让比赛自行其是的高尔夫球手很少能发挥出自己的潜力。他们打得很好，也许赢了一两次，但他们从未达到他们的天赋所要求的伟大高度。那些想要立即学习、变得更好并赢得胜利的玩家——就在这一秒，无需等待——就是那些超越自己自然能力并成为游戏中伟大成就者的人。</p></blockquote><p>哈蒙后来解释了为什么老虎是他见过的最没有耐心的人之一：</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>当泰格想要用他的高尔夫挥杆做某事时，他希望现在就完成。没有分阶段实施，也没有长期规划。一旦他决定做出改变，他就会立即彻底地做出改变。然后他衣衫褴褛地工作，直到完美为止，一路上几乎没有耐心。</p></blockquote><p>在哈蒙看来，耐心往往是一厢情愿的想法：对未来熟练程度的希望会阻止你今天真正致力于你想要提高的事情。</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading">每天五分钟的问题和学习困难的事情</h2><p>哈蒙的话让我想起了我在自我完善圈子里经常看到的一个现象。这种观点认为，对于学习来说，最重要的是在很长一段时间内每天做一点点事情。</p><p>这种方法的例子有：计划通过每天在 Duolingo 上玩五分钟来流利掌握一门语言的语言学习者、承诺每周写一页的未来小说家、或者每天拍摄一张照片的有抱负的摄影师。</p><p>阻止这种方法感觉很刻薄。毕竟，大多数人都没有为自己的愿望做任何事，所以做点什么，哪怕是一点点，也比什么都不做要好。不是吗？</p><p>然而，我不禁觉得这种方法类似于哈蒙的“耐心”高尔夫球手所体现的一厢情愿——他们利用最终掌握的缓慢来逃避艰巨的学习工作。</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading">最低限度习惯的逻辑</h2><p>此时，重新审视为什么这种方法在自我完善圈子中如此流行可能会有所帮助。 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Atomic-Habits-Proven-Build-Break/dp/0735211299/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2Y6PQC6WUTD4Y&amp;keywords=atomic+habits&amp;qid=1656002761&amp;sprefix=atomic+hab%2Caps%2C155&amp;sr=8-1">《原子习惯》</a>是我的朋友詹姆斯·克利尔写的一本精彩的畅销书，他是“从小事做起”自我完善方法最明显的支持者之一。</p><p>养成习惯的逻辑很引人注目：</p><ol><li>开始很难。</li><li>小习惯更容易养成。</li><li>一旦开始，就更容易提升并做更多事情。</li></ol><p>因此，按照逻辑，每天在 Duolingo 上花十分钟的人正在为练习与人交谈的更大习惯建立动力。通过降低进入门槛，他们开始了自我完善的过程，而过高的期望可能会让他们很难开始。</p><p>这样说来，最低限度习惯的逻辑是不可否认的。我认为这是开始做任何事情的重要行为技巧，尤其是当你想做的事情感觉不愉快时。当我不想锻炼时，我就用这种方法重新开始锻炼。我永远不会批评某人从较小的、令人愉快的习惯开始，闯入他们认为令人沮丧或不愉快但想要结果的事情。</p><p>我关心的是#3。从理论上讲，一旦开始，就很容易提高并做更多的事情。但在实践中，最小的习惯往往会成为目标，而不是为更大的事情做准备。我怀疑这种“耐心”的实践方法能否可靠地带来实质性的改进。</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> “耐心”的掌握方法有多有效？</h2><p>我不知道有任何研究专门将“每天五分钟”的习惯与人们想要掌握的技能的更典型的课程进行对比。纵向研究的成本和困难意味着在较长时间范围内的实证研究通常有些缺乏。</p><p>心理学上的<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spacing_effect">间隔效应</a>似乎支持缓慢、耐心的方法。当复习信息之间的间隔较长时，记忆往往比当相同的复习集中在一起时（例如临时抱佛脚考试时）更持久。然而，现实世界的语言学习研究<a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/02/07/learning-fast-or-slow/">往往发现相反的结果</a>，即更密集的课程比更延伸的方法更有优势。</p><p>我的猜测是，哪种方法更有效，是每天五分钟还是密集爆发，取决于所学技能的确切性质、所使用的练习活动以及学习者开始学习的知识。我怀疑复杂的技能倾向于更深入的方法，而广泛的、基于知识的科目倾向于更耐心的方法。<span id='easy-footnote-1-15198' class='easy-footnote-margin-adjust'></span> <span class='easy-footnote'><a href='https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/13/too-patient/#easy-footnote-bottom-1-15198' title="A full discussion of exactly what sorts of skills (or sub-skills) benefit from different learning schedules is outside the scope of this essay. Learning vocabulary via flashcards, for instance, seems well-suited to an extended schedule, but the procedural fluency needed for conversations probably benefits from a more intensive one. Similarly, learning about history by watching recorded lectures can probably be done leisurely, but developing the analytical skills of a historian will require a more focused approach. My point here is that my argument that certain categories of “long-term habits” are ineffective for their purpose shouldn’t be misconstrued as the opposite point that an intensive schedule is always better for acquiring all types of skills."><sup>1</sup></a></span></p><p> However this kind of analysis is probably beside the point because, in general, the sorts of things people do for learning when they opt for a five-minute daily habit are categorically different from those they would do in a typical classroom setting or as part of a focused learning project.</p><p> Here, “patient” approaches suffer from several serious drawbacks:</p><ul><li> <strong>Limited time constrains the types of practice you can do.</strong> In five minutes a day, you can complete an exercise on Duolingo, but meaningful conversation practice needs more time. Watching a video of someone painting can be done in five minutes, but replicating that painting yourself takes more time.</li><li> <strong>A focus on “sustainability” avoids necessary effort</strong> . When you pick activities designed to be sustainable over months or years, there&#39;s a bias against picking anything too effortful or time-consuming. This eliminates a lot of the intense, deliberate practice needed to achieve mastery.</li><li> <strong>Long timeframes make it harder to tell if you&#39;re making progress</strong> . Improvement is evident when you&#39;re learning a lot over a few months. If you&#39;re not making progress, you change your approach. When improvement is something expected to occur years in the future, how do you know if you&#39;re actually getting better at the underlying skill?</li></ul><p> For these reasons, I&#39;m skeptical of many of the proposed plans I&#39;ve heard from readers to achieve mastery via simple, long-term habits.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Mastery is Slow—and Impatient</h2><p> In his research on <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037%2F0033-295X.100.3.363">deliberate practice</a> , Anders Ericsson articulated the view of mastery that most closely corresponds with my own. He argued that mastery is a slow process, and also an impatient one:</p><ul><li> <strong>Mastery is slow because it takes a long time</strong> . No, <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/ultralearning/">my book</a> is not an exception to this. I do think it&#39;s possible to learn more efficiently, and that effectively-designed projects can help people accomplish more than they think possible. But genuine mastery (not just relatively quick intermediacy) requires a long time, and nothing I&#39;ve worked on is an exception to that rule.</li><li> <strong>Mastery is impatient because the work required is deliberate, effortful and striving</strong> . Deliberate practice was Ericsson&#39;s term to describe the kind of learning efforts put in by elite performers in chess, music and athletics. It clearly describes Tiger Woods, Harmon&#39;s most famous student.</li></ul><p> I believe this is true even if you don&#39;t aspire to world-class greatness. Even getting “good enough” requires a level of commitment that&#39;s difficult to reach with minimal habits alone.</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/13/too-patient/">The Problem with Being Too Patient</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>;</content:encoded><wfw:commentrss> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/13/too-patient/feed/</wfw:commentrss><slash:comments> 0</slash:comments></item><item><title> Why Flashcards Beat Mnemonics for Studying</title><link/> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/06/flashcards-vs-mnemonics/<comments> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/06/flashcards-vs-mnemonics/#respond</comments><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Young]]></dc:creator><pubDate> Tue, 06 Jun 2023 19:54:47 +0000</pubDate><category><![CDATA[General]]></category><guid ispermalink="false"> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/?p=15181 </guid><description><![CDATA[<p> Flashcards should be the base for learning any memory-intensive subject, mnemonics layered on top (if that).</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/06/flashcards-vs-mnemonics/">Why Flashcards Beat Mnemonics for Studying</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>; </description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p> Suppose you have to memorize a lot of material—vocabulary words in a new language, terminology for an anatomy class, legal precedents, or dates of historical events. Which strategy will lead to better performance: mnemonics or flashcards? </p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="512" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying1-1024x512.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15188" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying1-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying1-300x150.jpg 300w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying1-768x384.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying1-1536x768.jpg 1536w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying1.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p> In the small and strange world of studying strategies, mnemonics techniques receive a lot of attention:</p><ul><li> The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vocabulary#The_keyword_method">keyword method</a> allows you to memorize a word by linking it through an intermediate and fantastical picture. The French word <em>chavirer</em> , which means to capsize, gets transliterated into “shave an ear,” and you picture a bearded ear shaving itself in a canoe that&#39;s tipping over.</li><li> The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mnemonic_peg_system">peg method</a> first links images to numbers (one is “bun,” two is “shoe,” etc..) and then combines these into elaborate visual imagery to encode and recall arbitrary numbers and dates.</li><li> The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Method_of_loci">memory palace</a> uses a mental stroll through a familiar location. You insert fantastical imagery along a pre-remembered linear sequence, allowing you to graft arbitrary information onto this prior structure. </li></ul><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="512" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying3-1024x512.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15189" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying3-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying3-300x150.jpg 300w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying3-768x384.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying3-1536x768.jpg 1536w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying3.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p> In <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Moonwalking-Einstein-Science-Remembering-Everything/dp/B0716V44N3/ref=sr_1_1?hvadid=229990287774&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvlocphy=9001551&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvqmt=e&amp;hvrand=12601732232583394634&amp;hvtargid=kwd-297899628933&amp;hydadcr=3320_10311061&amp;keywords=moonwalking+with+einstein&amp;qid=1685725465&amp;sr=8-1">Moonwalking with Einstein</a> , the writer Joshua Foer explored his dive into elite memory competitions, where people memorize the order of a deck of cards in under a minute, learn the values of pi to thousands of decimal places, or develop perfect recall of unfamiliar texts, verbatim, in only slightly more time than it takes to read them.</p><p> Given these impressive results, starting with mnemonics for any skill that depends heavily on memory would seem a no-brainer.</p><p> In contrast, flashcards are, well, kinda boring. Everyone has done them before. They&#39;re dry and elementary. You put a question on one side, the answer on the other and you drill (and drill and drill) until you can do them without thinking. No fantastical imagery or secret method. Just repetition.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Flashcards are Underrated</h2><p> While mnemonics might seem like the obvious choice for learning a ton of new information, research rigorously comparing the efficacy of various studying strategies paints a somewhat different picture.</p><p> In their excellent review of <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/stoken/rbtfl/Z10jaVH/60XQM/full">ten popular studying techniques</a> , Dunlosky and colleagues summarized the research on both the keyword mnemonic method and practice testing (which includes flashcards). In this review, practice testing got the highest possible rating for usefulness, while the keyword mnemonic got a low grade.</p><p> The keyword method does work—that is, students who use it tend to remember the words they were memorizing better than those who didn&#39;t. But it had a number of limitations:</p><ul><li> <strong>It takes time to learn and teach mnemonic methods.</strong> Unlike flashcards, mnemonics is itself a skill that requires considerable practice to get good at. While this may benefit elite mnemonists, it may not be worth the additional investment for those who simply want to learn Spanish, law or anatomy.</li><li> <strong>Mnemonics often take a good deal of time, especially for beginners.</strong> It may take a few minutes to create a good link with the keyword method, in which time you could have done several repetitions with flashcards. One study, which equalized the time-on-task between mnemonics and more rote memorization, found that simply increasing repetition provided an advantage over using the mnemonic.</li><li> <strong>Mnemonics greatly assist with recall over relatively short intervals, but their benefits might not endure.</strong> This makes mnemonics useful in memory competitions—events that require memorization of highly arbitrary information with near-immediate recall. In contrast, much of what we&#39;re trying to memorize needs to stay in our heads for much longer.</li></ul><p> Flashcards, in contrast, are simple and quick. While all memory fades eventually, the repetitive overlearning caused by flashcards is one of the more durable ways to create long-term learning.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Direct Retrieval is the End Goal of Learning</h2><p> Empirically, mnemonics are a bit of a mixed bag. Flashcards seem to have the advantage, at least in carefully controlled studies of longer-term recollection in students who aren&#39;t already trained in mnemonic techniques.</p><p> Cognitive theory also lends support to this perspective. A major feature of skill acquisition is that the methods used to achieve a result are not constant. For <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Emerging-Minds-Process-Childrens-Thinking-ebook/dp/B000QTD49E/ref=tmm_kin_swatch_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;qid=&amp;sr=">instance</a> , children learning simple addition start by counting both numbers on their hands, then count from the bigger number and finally retrieve the answer directly.</p><p> As expertise develops, more elaborate methods tend to be replaced by direct retrieval of the answer. This is one reason that expertise can be relatively effortless—instead of going through an elaborate process to get to an answer, you just remember it.</p><p> Mnemonics, in this light, can be seen a little bit like the finger-counting. The vivid imagery acts as a bridge between two concepts that would otherwise be difficult to associate. You can quickly learn the mnemonic and it enabling you to cross over from one idea to the other. However, if you practice enough, the two ideas get directly associated—with no intervening imagery.</p><p> For situations where fluency is particularly important, such as recalling vocabulary words while speaking, the direct retrieval option is perhaps necessary for a majority of words in order to not get bogged down while speaking too much. This suggests that even if you initially learn a word via mnemonics, direct retrieval will eventually take over as it becomes the faster option.</p><p> This suggests that mnemonics are, at best, a temporary measure. They may make learning an association easier, in the short-to-medium term, for words that haven&#39;t been sufficiently overlearned to form a direct association. </p><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="512" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying2-1024x512.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15190" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying2-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying2-300x150.jpg 300w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying2-768x384.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying2-1536x768.jpg 1536w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/06/Why-Flashcards-are-Better-than-Mnemonics-for-Studying2.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><h2 class="wp-block-heading">为什么不兼得？</h2><p> Of course, flashcards and mnemonics are not mutually exclusive. You can use the keyword mnemonic when you first encounter a flashcard and then study it repeatedly. In this way, the temporary bridge offered by the mnemonic may be beneficial to learning.</p><p> This is the approach I&#39;ve used when I&#39;ve had to memorize a lot of material. I start with the keyword mnemonic, when that is relatively easy to do, and follow with a lot of spaced retrieval practice to make the association automatic and robust.</p><p> However, I think it&#39;s worth examining the relative efficacy of the two techniques for a few reasons:</p><ul><li> <strong>Many people get overly excited about mnemonics and use them instead of flashcards.</strong> I think this is often ill-advised for the reasons I&#39;ve articulated above.</li><li> <strong>Sometimes the material isn&#39;t mnemonics-friendly.</strong> I found the keyword mnemonic great for learning vocabulary in European languages—but far less helpful for Asian languages. The “sounds like” method doesn&#39;t easily discriminate between words in Chinese (which all sound like each other much more than they sound like words in English) so the first leg in the bridge is weak. However flashcards continued to work and were my primary tool for learning Chinese and Korean vocabulary.</li><li> <strong>For those not trained in mnemonics, it&#39;s worth asking how much time should be invested in acquiring the skills needed.</strong> While mnemonics have some valid use cases, they are often slow and cumbersome without lots of practice, meaning they are best reserved for situations where they&#39;re likely to be used across many memory-intensive subjects.</li></ul><p> In short, if you are proficient with mnemonics, by all means, use them to supplement your flashcards. If you&#39;re not, or your subject makes using them difficult, or you simply aren&#39;t sure which one to prioritize, stick with the flashcards.</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/06/flashcards-vs-mnemonics/">Why Flashcards Beat Mnemonics for Studying</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>;</content:encoded><wfw:commentrss> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/06/06/flashcards-vs-mnemonics/feed/</wfw:commentrss><slash:comments> 0</slash:comments></item><item><title> When is Learning Worth the Effort?</title><link/> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/30/learning-cost-benefit/<comments> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/30/learning-cost-benefit/#respond</comments><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Young]]></dc:creator><pubDate> Tue, 30 May 2023 16:30:11 +0000</pubDate><category><![CDATA[General]]></category><guid ispermalink="false"> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/?p=15172 </guid><description><![CDATA[<p> Do we underinvest in learning? An exploration of the logic of learn-or-delegate decisions.</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/30/learning-cost-benefit/">When is Learning Worth the Effort?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>; </description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p> One of the few lessons I recall from business school is the <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/m/make-or-buy-decision.asp">make-or-buy decision</a> . Big companies often face a choice: should they make something in-house, or outsource it to a supplier?</p><p> The decision depends on many factors, but a big part is cost: will it be cheaper or more reliable if you invest in in-house production? Or does it make more sense to pay someone else to do it?</p><p> Decisions about whether or not to learn something are often similar. For almost any conceivable skill you can:</p><ol><li> Learn to do it yourself.</li><li> Hire someone else to do it.</li><li> Avoid doing it entirely.</li></ol><p> Consider programming. You could learn to write code, hire a programmer to do it for you, or choose work and projects that don&#39;t require you to create software.</p><p> Or language learning. You could learn to speak Mandarin, hire a translator, or avoid doing business with monolingual Mandarin speakers.</p><p> The same choice applies to countless other skills, from understanding the tax code to applying medical advice, repairing drywall or planting a garden. You can learn, outsource or avoid.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Learning Rarely Makes Sense Short-Term</h2><p> One common feature of this problem is that the costs of learning rarely make sense if you&#39;re only thinking about immediate benefits. Even if you&#39;re the smartest person on earth, hiring a Mandarin translator, Java programmer or car mechanic to deal with your problem still takes less time and energy than learning to solve it yourself from scratch.</p><p> Yet, if you already know how to solve a problem, doing it yourself is often (but not always) the most effective option. Hiring people takes time, increases the possibility they won&#39;t understand or be able to deliver what you want and can be more expensive.</p><p> Viewed this way, the optimal point for many learn-or-delegate decisions depends on your prior expertise: </p><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="512" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort1-1024x512.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15173" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort1-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort1-300x150.jpg 300w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort1-768x384.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort1-1536x768.jpg 1536w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort1.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div><p> This analysis suggests you should do what you&#39;re good at, and delegate what you&#39;re not.</p><p> The major wrinkle in this approach is that <em>your level of expertise isn&#39;t constant</em> . It varies depending on the amount of practice you&#39;ve had on the problem. One of the most famous empirical results is the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Power_law_of_practice">power law of practice</a> , suggesting that many aspects of proficiency follow a roughly power-law relationship with the amount of practice.</p><p> The answer to the learn-or-delegate decision doesn&#39;t depend only on your current level of expertise, but also on how often you expect to perform the skill. If you&#39;re currently below the competency threshold where doing it yourself makes sense but will probably use the skill a lot, the total lifetime cost of learning may end up being less than delegating: </p><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="512" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort2-1024x512.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15174" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort2-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort2-300x150.jpg 300w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort2-768x384.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort2-1536x768.jpg 1536w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/When-is-Learning-Worth-the-Effort2.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div><p> While I&#39;m using an economic lens here, the reasoning still applies outside your job. How much I enjoy painting as a hobby depends on how good I feel I am at it. Thus there&#39;s often an implicit learn-or-ignore decision with recreational activities that follows the same trade-off.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Do We Underinvest in Learning?</h2><p> To summarize, many decisions about learning have the following features:</p><ul><li> Doing it yourself doesn&#39;t initially pass a cost-benefit test.</li><li> The more you practice, the lower the cost becomes.</li><li> Thus whether it&#39;s “worth it” to learn something depends on a far-sighted calculation of how much you&#39;ll need to use the skill.</li></ul><p> Unfortunately our intrinsic motivational system is <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2020/12/14/procrastinate-expert/">remarkably short-term in its focus</a> . Immediate costs or payoffs influence our decision far more than long-term ones. Experiments show people often pay steep discount rates for delayed rewards, in <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2020/11/02/motivation/#07-02">ways that are inconsistent</a> with any rational agent (even an extremely impulsive one).</p><p> This suggests we may be underinvesting in learning. We&#39;re disinclined to practice skills that fail an initial cost-benefit analysis—even if our investment of practice would be profitable over the course of our lifetime.</p><p> This insight helped Vat and me while learning other languages. The costs of practicing a language are relatively high when you&#39;re not consistently using it. In the short term, forcing yourself to interact in a new language is also costly. But, if you practice enough, speaking the language of the country you&#39;re visiting becomes easier than sticking entirely within an English bubble. Adults are resourceful and frequently find ways to avoid using an unfamiliar language; the consequence is that few get anything close to the levels of exposure that young children can&#39;t help but get when learning.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Matthew Effects in Learning</h2><p> Another consequence of this basic model is that we should expect Matthew Effects in learning.</p><p> <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matthew_effect">The Matthew Effect</a> was first coined by sociologists Robert Merton and Harriet Zuckerman in their study of elite scientists. Eminent scientists often get more credit than unknown researchers for similar work, meaning that, over time, eminence tends to compound while less famous academics linger in obscurity.<span id='easy-footnote-1-15172' class='easy-footnote-margin-adjust'></span> <span class='easy-footnote'><a href='https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/30/learning-cost-benefit/#easy-footnote-bottom-1-15172' title="The name of the effect comes from the parable of the talents in the Gospel of Matthew, &amp;#8220;For to every one who has will more be given, and he will have abundance; but from him who has not, even what he has will be taken away.&amp;#8221;"><sup>1</sup></a></span></p><p> Later, psychologist Keith Stanovich applied <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/0022057409189001-204?journalCode=jexa">the same insight to reading</a> . Those with a slight advantage in early reading ability had a slightly reduced cost of reading new material. This lead to them practicing more, further reducing the costs of reading. Given the connection between reading and other forms of learning, he even hypothesized that early reading ability might bootstrap intelligence by making it easier to acquire new skills and knowledge.</p><p> Research bears out Stanovich&#39;s hypothesis. In <a href="https://srcd.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/cdev.12272">a study looking at identical twins</a> who varied in early reading ability, the slightly more proficient twin later showed gains in intelligence compared with their genetically-identical sibling. Skills beget skills; knowledge begets knowledge.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Specialization and Focusing on Strengths</h2><p> At this point, it&#39;s helpful to clarify. I&#39;m not suggesting that since learned skills get easier with practice, we should do everything for ourselves and never delegate.</p><p> This is false, even by the basic logic I&#39;ve spelled out above. Some tasks simply aren&#39;t encountered frequently enough to cross the cost/benefit threshold. I may never have an opportunity to speak Mongolian, so if I ever meet a monolingual Mongolian speaker, I&#39;d be happy to lean on Google Translate.</p><p> Additionally, we can&#39;t consider skills in isolation. Spending time learning one thing is an implicit decision not to learn something else. I could learn French, but that time is taken away from learning Mandarin. I could learn Javascript, but that time can&#39;t also be spent learning Python.</p><p> Ultimately, specialization, not self-sufficiency, is the road to abundance in the world we live in today. We delegate the vast majority of skills in our lives, not because learning them all is impossible, but because getting really good at one thing makes sense when it&#39;s relatively easy to delegate everything else.</p><p> Despite spending years learning programming, I do virtually none of it for my own business. Given that my writing is central to my business, and I don&#39;t have enough time to do all the writing I&#39;d like, hiring other people to do the programming <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparative_advantage">makes more sense</a> . Those people, in turn, tend to be much further along the expertise curve than I am because they&#39;ve made a similar decision to specialize.</p><p> That being said, there are many instances where skills can&#39;t easily be delegated. I might be able to hire out behind-the-scenes programming for my website, but it doesn&#39;t save effort or cost to hire someone to read the research used to write the articles. If I don&#39;t understand the research, I can&#39;t weave it into the text I&#39;m producing.</p><p> In other cases, delegation is an imperfect or inconvenient substitute for being able to do something yourself. Relying on a translator is not equivalent to being able to speak the language yourself when you move to another country. Being able to read a text isn&#39;t made redundant if someone narrates it to you aloud. Thus being able to speak the language of the country you live in and being able to read are skills that are almost certainly worth mastering.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Thinking about Learning in the Long-Term</h2><p> I find it useful to keep in mind a few things when I face resistance to learning something new:</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 1. How much can I expect this skill to get easier with more practice?</h3><p> One way to estimate this is to look at people with varying degrees of experience. How much effort did it take them to do what you struggle with? The learning curve is quite steep for some skills—you get good relatively quickly. For others, the curve is flat for a long time—you may need to practice for years before you feel it&#39;s worth the effort.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 2. How much would I use the skill if I was better at it?</h3><p> Supposing you could reach the relatively flat part of the practice curve, how much would you use it?</p><p> If you live in a country that speaks a language you don&#39;t know, learning that language would definitely pass the cost-benefit test. Learning a major world language you might use in work or educational contexts probably also does. A niche language that isn&#39;t spoken much … maybe not? In this case, it may only be worth learning if you have a strong intrinsic motivation to learn it.</p><p> If a skill is central to your career, it may easily be worth the cost, even if it is initially difficult for you to learn. In contrast, a career skill that doesn&#39;t fit well with your existing skills may go unused even if you&#39;re nearly an expert—it&#39;s simply cheaper to outsource.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 3. How much would I enjoy the skill, conditional on being better at it?</h3><p> Economic rewards aren&#39;t the only motivation. If you&#39;re good at something, you tend to enjoy it more and draw personal satisfaction. But that&#39;s more true of some skills than others. You might be particularly proud of being able to paint a realistic landscape but not feel too special about being able to file your taxes quickly.</p><p> Deciding when it makes sense to learn isn&#39;t trivial, but given that our intuitions often give us a misleadingly short-term picture of what&#39;s possible, it can be helpful to think more deeply about it.</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/30/learning-cost-benefit/">When is Learning Worth the Effort?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>;</content:encoded><wfw:commentrss> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/30/learning-cost-benefit/feed/</wfw:commentrss><slash:comments> 0</slash:comments></item><item><title> Seven Steps for Making a Solid Studying Plan</title><link/> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/23/studying-plan/<comments> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/23/studying-plan/#respond</comments><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Young]]></dc:creator><pubDate> Tue, 23 May 2023 15:50:00 +0000</pubDate><category><![CDATA[General]]></category><guid ispermalink="false"> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/?p=15151 </guid><description><![CDATA[<p> Need to learn something difficult? Here&#39;s how to make a studying plan that actually works!</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/23/studying-plan/">Seven Steps for Making a Solid Studying Plan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>; </description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p> A studying plan organizes three things:</p><ol><li> What you have to learn.</li><li> How you&#39;re going to learn it.</li><li> When you&#39;re going to invest the time.</li></ol><p> Although it sounds simple, most students don&#39;t make a detailed study plan. Of those that do, they often make mistakes that render the plan highly unrealistic—a recipe for future guilt, not future learning.</p><p> In this article, I&#39;m going to outline how to make a studying plan—and how you can stick to it.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Why Make a Studying Plan?</h2><p> Learning is effortful. Although that effort can be enjoyable, our impulses about what to do in the moment often don&#39;t coincide with what would maximize learning. Indeed, the research shows that students frequently <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/00461528209529247">choose activities</a> that feel fun but don&#39;t deliver results.</p><p> A good analogy is exercise. While playing a sport or going for a jog can be fun, our brains are designed to avoid unnecessary physical exertion. That&#39;s why you rarely see anyone over the age of ten running down the street unless they&#39;re late for an appointment.</p><p> If you want to develop fitness without injuring yourself, it helps to have a workout plan you can and will stick to, rather than just going to the gym whenever you feel like and working on whatever equipment you stumble into.</p><p> The logic is the same for studying. Having a plan maximizes the chance of investing effort where it counts to create learning.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Step One: Review Your Materials </h2><figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="512" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/HP2-1024x512.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15162" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/HP2-1024x512.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/HP2-300x150.jpg 300w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/HP2-768x384.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/HP2-1536x768.jpg 1536w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/HP2.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure><p> I&#39;m assuming you&#39;ve already chosen some class, book, tutorials or other curriculum to guide you. (If you haven&#39;t, the first step is to do your research and find a good resource for the skill you&#39;re trying to learn!)</p><p> The starting point is to review your curriculum and figure out:</p><ul><li> What are the lessons you&#39;ll need to watch/read/review?</li><li> What are the practice activities you need to engage in?</li><li> What are the required deliverables (essays/homework) you need to complete?</li><li> How will you need to use the skills and knowledge you&#39;ve gained? Consider things like the format of the final exam as well as where you plan to apply the skills and knowledge you&#39;re learning.</li></ul><p> A pure practice project may be an exception. In this kind of project, you&#39;re not working off materials but trying to practice or implement knowledge you&#39;ve gained elsewhere. For a practice project, you&#39;re creating your own curriculum, so you can choose your own pace. These tend to be more successful when you&#39;ve gone beyond the beginner period and can more successfully guide your own practice.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Step Two: Calculate Your Minimum Time Investment</h2><p> The minimum time investment includes all the work you must put in to complete the class as specified.这包括：</p><ul><li> How long will it take to do the required readings?</li><li> How long will it take to watch any videos/lectures/lessons?</li><li> How long will it take to finish the required deliverables (homework, essays, projects)?</li></ul><p> Videos and recorded lectures are easy to estimate: you can add up the run time of all the videos. Will you be able to <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2022/01/17/faster-listening-works/">watch at an accelerated pace</a> ? If so, you can divide the total by the estimated playback rate (eg, 1.5 or 2 times speed). Otherwise, this time is a fixed amount based on how long the lessons are.</p><p> For required readings, you need an estimate of your reading rate. You can get a first approximation by timing yourself reading a few pages and extrapolating that to the whole book. Read slowly and deliberately; the speed for long reading sessions is inevitably slower than a few-minute sprint.</p><p> Homework is hard to estimate in advance, but you may be able to get an estimate from the course provider, teacher or past students.</p><p> The general idea here is to calculate the minimum time investment to work through the materials you&#39;ve been provided—without any additional studying.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Step Three: Estimate Additional Studying Time Needs</h2><p> For some classes, simply doing all the work assigned will allow you to pass the test and apply it in real life. But for most classes, you&#39;ll have to go beyond this.</p><p> Some additional places you might expect to invest time are:</p><ul><li> Extra practice questions/homework.</li><li> Application to real-life problems and contexts.</li><li> Creating/reviewing flashcards.</li><li> Self-explanations, such as the <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2011/09/01/learn-faster/">Feynman Technique</a> .</li><li> Extra research not mentioned in the syllabus.</li></ul><p> A good way to estimate this is by looking at your personal historical data: how much time have you typically needed to invest, beyond the minimum curriculum, to achieve the results you want from the class? There&#39;s no “correct” answer here. Some classes are time-intensive, and the required material is challenging to get through. Other classes are sparse and leave it to students to master the material on their own.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Step Four: Schedule Studying in Your Calendar</h2><p> Once you have an itemized list of your expected time investment, you need to figure out when you&#39;re actually going to do everything.</p><p> Put any due dates, exams, live lectures or lessons directly in your calendar. For reading, working on homework, practice efforts and other forms of studying, you should still allocate time for them, but there are two different ways to do it:</p><ul><li> <strong>The most rigorous option is to schedule everything as an appointment.</strong> I recommend this approach if studying has to fit inside an already crowded schedule. So if you&#39;re a busy parent and professional studying for a licensing exam, you&#39;d better put studying time directly in your calendar, or it will get pushed to the side in the moment.</li><li> <strong>The more flexible option is to create a weekly or daily routine.</strong> The exact activities in each block would vary depending on your goals, but the time commitments themselves would be relatively routine. For instance, you might decide to study every morning before work, or in the evenings, or on weekends.</li></ul><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Step Five: Sanity Check</h2><p> At this point in the process, we can do a basic sanity check: how does your calculated time investment from Step Two and Step Three compare with the time you&#39;ve scheduled?   If your available time for the project is less than the estimated minimum, you&#39;ve already got a non-starter. You need to clear more time in your schedule, rethink the aims of the learning project, or expand the timeline you are allowing to complete it.</p><p> If your available time is slightly over what you&#39;ve budgeted, you have little room for error. Getting sick, an unexpectedly challenging topic or a surprise interruption could derail the whole project.</p><p> If you have substantially more time available than you&#39;ve budgeted, that&#39;s not necessarily a sign to relax. With too much slack, you might not feel the pressure to study when you need to and end up wasting time procrastinating. In those cases, I recommend setting soft deadlines that push the work ahead of the more relaxed schedule. This approach can keep the pressure comfortable but challenging, so you have more room for error later.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Step Six: Getting Feedback</h2><p> Making a plan is the easy part. The hard part is sticking to it. Fortunately, if you keep an eye on the feedback you&#39;re getting while you&#39;re studying and adjust accordingly, the plan you make can be an invaluable guide rather than something that gets tossed aside at the first brush with difficulty.</p><p> Consider these sources of feedback:</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 1. Feedback on sticking to your schedule.</h3><p> The first source of feedback is your ability to implement the plan. A helpful strategy is simply to write your intention on an agenda or planner each day and then record what you actually did. For example, you might have intended to study for three hours on Wednesday, but you were interrupted and only got in two hours.</p><p> Whenever there are deviations from your plan, it&#39;s helpful to note the source of the obstacle. Even though you can&#39;t control everything that deflects you from your plan, few obstacles are insurmountable if you can recognize them.考虑：</p><ul><li> <strong>Deviations due to interruptions from others.</strong> Communicate boundaries for your studying time so others appreciate its importance. If you can&#39;t avoid interruptions, find fall-back studying slots in your schedule to make up for occasional, unavoidable interruptions.</li><li> <strong>Deviations from lack of preparation.</strong> Your computer died. You couldn&#39;t log into your account to access the lesson. You had to buy colored pencils. Find a way to do these things before your scheduled session or eliminate them as unnecessary.</li><li> <strong>Deviations because of procrastination/motivation.</strong> Use the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique">Pomodoro technique</a> , lower your expectations for proficiency in the session to avoid perfectionism, or alternate between reading/practice to avoid mind wandering or boredom.</li></ul><p> Learning is effortful and genuine obstacles can arise, making it hard to stick to one&#39;s plan. However, if you can identify what is causing the interruptions, you can find remedies in many cases.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 2. Feedback on your learning progress.</h3><p> The second source of feedback concerns your progress in learning. Sometimes skills and subjects gel instantly, and you don&#39;t need to review them. In other cases, the new material can seem bewildering and exceed your estimates of how long it will take to master.</p><p> Once again, the key is to observe the feedback and break it down:</p><ul><li> <strong>Are you struggling because the basics aren&#39;t firmly entrenched?</strong> Drills, flashcards and repeated practice on simple problems can help fix this.</li><li> <strong>Are you struggling because you don&#39;t understand a difficult idea?</strong> Self-explanations, talking to teachers/peers/tutors and finding alternative explanatory sources can be helpful.</li><li> <strong>Are you struggling because you can&#39;t see what you&#39;re doing wrong or how to improve it?</strong> Seeking coaching, corrective feedback or guidance may be helpful.</li></ul><p> The more granular you can be in identifying your problems, the easier they are to resolve. Zooming in on particular concepts, movements, facts or procedures is the key to getting past difficulties.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Step Seven: Making Modifications</h2><p> Once you&#39;ve gotten some feedback, you may need to modify your plan. That might involve increasing the hours you invest if you&#39;re falling behind, or you might change your routine so that you can actually invest the hours you said you would.</p><p> In the end, you may not stick to your plan with total rigidity. The primary benefit of planning isn&#39;t to eliminate all improvisation and flexibility. Rather it&#39;s to marshal the resources of time and energy needed to learn and identify obstacles ahead of time so you can avoid most of them. What&#39;s ultimately useful is less the plan itself, but the thinking that goes into creating it.</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/23/studying-plan/">Seven Steps for Making a Solid Studying Plan</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>;</content:encoded><wfw:commentrss> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/23/studying-plan/feed/</wfw:commentrss><slash:comments> 0</slash:comments></item><item><title> Some Thoughts on Becoming Self-Actualized</title><link/> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/16/becoming-self-actualized/<comments> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/16/becoming-self-actualized/#respond</comments><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Young]]></dc:creator><pubDate> Tue, 16 May 2023 15:35:00 +0000</pubDate><category><![CDATA[General]]></category><guid ispermalink="false"> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/?p=15136 </guid><description><![CDATA[<p> Why do people sometimes abruptly become a better version of themselves? Why are such moments relatively rare?</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/16/becoming-self-actualized/">Some Thoughts on Becoming Self-Actualized</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>; </description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p> A reader emailed me citing a few examples of people who abruptly changed their lives: they started exercising, built better habits, studied hard and got good grades, moved up in their careers … basically turning themselves into “successful” people seemingly overnight. He wanted to understand why this happens and ask how someone might attempt a similar transformation.</p><p> I&#39;ve witnessed this kind of personality change in others several times, so I believe the phenomenon is real. A number of my friends suddenly became much more motivated, conscientious, organized and ambitious—often translating into better life outcomes for themselves.</p><p> It&#39;s also something I&#39;ve personally experienced. When I was around fifteen, I changed my diet, started waking up early, exercising regularly, reading books and trying various ways to be more productive. While the transition took place over a couple of years rather than a singular moment, it still a rather abrupt directional change in my personality that has culminated in who I am today. </p><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/2-exercise_blog.png" alt="" width="600" height="600"/></figure></div><p> Assuming, for a second, that my introspective self-report and anecdotal observations are accurate, I think the reader&#39;s question is important and merits further discussion. Why do people sometimes abruptly become better versions of themselves? Perhaps more importantly, why does it so often seem to fail?</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Discovering Self-Actualization</h2><p> For lack of a better term, I&#39;ll call this kind of transformation discovering self-actualization. That sounds vague, but it&#39;s the best way I can describe the experience. If you&#39;re allergic to self-help jargon, perhaps another way of describing it might be “becoming an adult” or “getting your act together.” </p><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/mirror-you.png" alt=""/></figure></div><p> In my case, I think the changes were triggered by a fundamental restructuring of my belief system. Namely, I began to believe that there is considerable room for autonomy in making decisions over my life and that, if I chose wisely, those decisions could make a big difference in where my life ended up.</p><p> Wanting to start my own business was also a significant trigger. Something about the intrinsic appeal of being my own boss and having complete financial independence, combined with the inherent difficulty in succeeding in that goal, acted as a catalyst. Indeed, I&#39;ve known quite a few people who have discovered self-actualization in the context of professional ambition.</p><p> For other people, the trigger was something more concrete. They read a particular book that changed their worldview ( <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Getting_Things_Done">Getting Things Done</a> , for many). They encountered a new-to-them religion, philosophy or spiritual practice ( <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mindfulness">mindfulness meditation</a> seems to be another common trigger for change).</p><p> Even if the exact cause is idiosyncratic, I see a few common features:</p><ul><li> <strong>A belief that there are lives better than the one we are currently living.</strong> The central premise is that there&#39;s a broad array of possible futures, and many of them are better than the default. This seems to hold even in philosophical views that reject most kinds of ambition. For instance, those interested in mindfulness meditation often spurn the idea that career ambitions should be made central to life. But they still believe that mindfulness will let them experience a better quality of life.</li><li> <strong>A sudden, pervasive increase in self-efficacy.</strong> While <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-efficacy">Bandura&#39;s original concept</a> was decidedly granular, there do appear to be moments where you become more confident in succeeding at a broader range of actions.</li><li> <strong>Increased valuation of delaying gratification and resisting impulses.</strong> The willingness to work hard, do things that make you feel uncomfortable and resist your immediate habits and impulses is also at work. Over a relatively short period, someone who might have struggled with sticking to an exercise program is suddenly taking on dozens of high-effort challenges.</li><li> <strong>(Over)zealous application of the above changes.</strong> Often, people who experience a major paradigm shift are overly optimistic about the value of alternate versions of their life, overly confident about their ability to execute, and overly focused on self-improvement over momentary gratification.</li></ul><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> The Skeptic&#39;s Critique</h2><p> Of course, I&#39;m far from the first to notice this phenomenon. A lot of self-help gurus have built their entire marketing empires around selling people transformative life change. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tony_Robbins">Tony Robbins</a> , in particular, seems to make a big deal about these kinds of moments.</p><p> The skeptic would argue that these kinds of changes don&#39;t typically last. Hype fades, and while getting excited about something is easy, we rarely change our personality or behavior permanently.</p><p> I tend to agree with the skeptic—most of the time. I suspect that most people experience one or, maybe, two of these shifts in their entire life. Many people may never experience it. Change, instead, is generally gradual and directionless. Sometimes we get in a bit better shape, sometimes we let ourselves go. Most bursts of self-improvement revert to the mean.</p><p> However, given the significance of these dramatic shifts, we shouldn&#39;t round their probability to zero. Experiencing such a moment once or twice in your life might make up for dozens of other fizzled attempts at bettering yourself.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading">为什么会发生这种情况？ Why Does it Fail?</h2><p> My speculative theory of these kinds of personal transformations is:</p><ul><li> <strong>There&#39;s a temporary change in your optimism, confidence and valuing of effort.</strong> This kind of momentary effect can come from reading a self-help book, having a role model who inspires you to work at something, or having a private epiphany.</li><li> <strong>The environment creates a self-sustaining feedback loop.</strong> The easiest way to see this kind of positive feedback loop would be setting a goal, achieving it, and suddenly biasing your other estimates of self-efficacy or confidence upward.</li><li> <strong>Once the initial feedback loop wears off, you&#39;re already in a sufficiently “different” position for your life.</strong> Your habits and material circumstances of personal identity have shifted to a new equilibrium position, and you now maintain it.</li></ul><p> Under this theory, most self-improvement efforts fizzle because the momentary burst of enthusiasm doesn&#39;t generate a self-sustaining feedback loop, and the equilibrium you reach is <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2015/03/25/permanent-habits/">metastable</a> . Eventually you decay back to the person you were before because a lot of gravity is pulling you back that way.</p><p> Even when this kind of transformative change occurs, I think there are probably limits on how far it can go. People&#39;s <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2020/10/20/change-yourself/">beliefs about their malleability</a> vary wildly around the actual figure. Some people suddenly become incredibly optimistic about their ability to become popular, successful, smart, enlightened, etc., as well as the converse, where people adopt a fixed view of themselves and believe change is impossible.</p><p> The transformations I&#39;ve witnessed in other people tend to involve modestly unrealistic beliefs. This raises an interesting question of whether some amount of self-delusion helps in crossing over into a new equilibrium, even if it&#39;s unsustainable. Were that true, though much-maligned by skeptics, this small break from reality may actually be key—a truly sober assessment of one&#39;s possibilities may not encourage enough of a transitory change in your beliefs to shift over to a new equilibrium.</p><p> At the same time, it also seems clear that most changes are not of this magnitude. Discovering that you can take charge of your life is probably something you can only really do once or twice in your life. Once that&#39;s firmly established in your beliefs, further adjustments are probably minor in comparison—tweaks to your habits, skills or perspective.</p><p> Since the world is flush with people pitching and persuading others to adopt a self-actualization belief set (even if it is partly delusional), a related question is why such transformations are relatively rare. My suspicion is that they&#39;re harder to sustain because while it&#39;s easy to find sources of inspiration, it&#39;s much harder to locate the positive feedback loops that keep the motivation going.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Can You Trigger a Change in Yourself?</h2><p> Given that many of us would like to have a sudden, positive shift in the direction of our lives, is there anything we can do to facilitate this kind of transition? </p><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/beyond_blog.png" alt=""/></figure></div><p>我不知道。 While I&#39;ve witnessed it many times, the change itself happens as a by-product of something else rather than the person actively seeking it out.</p><p> However, I do think there are a few generic ingredients that may increase the likelihood of such a change:</p><ul><li> <strong>Success with self-set ambitions.</strong> Self-efficacy seems to be a crucial motivational component here. It&#39;s not enough to know that building a business, learning a language or getting in shape is possible. You have to believe <em>you</em> could do it. While achieving one thing doesn&#39;t necessarily translate to across-the-board motivation, having more success is likely to encourage increased self-efficacy.</li><li> <strong>Reading a lot of books with inspiring-but-credible messages.</strong> If modest self-delusion plays a role in initiating these transitions, the temporary boost you get from reading motivational material may increase your chances of hitting an inflection point. But inspiration fails if you don&#39;t believe it. Hence, finding optimistic sources that seem credible to you is more important than just picking the cheesiest self-help title.</li><li> <strong>Finding challenging, worthwhile goals.</strong> At least in my own case, I felt like the desire to start a business was a catalyst. The combination of an attractive goal and knowing I wouldn&#39;t succeed unless I worked really hard seemed vital.</li><li> <strong>More randomness.</strong> A final catalyst is having experiences that take you outside your comfort zone. The idea here is that greater variability in your day-to-day experience increases the likelihood of stumbling upon a positive feedback loop that alters your course in life.</li></ul><p> In the end, I&#39;m not entirely sure why some people become obsessed with personal productivity, mindfulness meditation, exercising daily, building a business or becoming a straight-A student. I don&#39;t know why the direction of their life seems to pivot abruptly after a particular experience. But I agree with the reader who emailed me that even if such transitions are rare, they seem important and poorly understood.</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/16/becoming-self-actualized/">Some Thoughts on Becoming Self-Actualized</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>;</content:encoded><wfw:commentrss> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/16/becoming-self-actualized/feed/</wfw:commentrss><slash:comments> 0</slash:comments></item><item><title> Ten Great Books on How to Learn Better</title><link/> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/10/10-best-learning-books/<comments> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/10/10-best-learning-books/#respond</comments><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Young]]></dc:creator><pubDate> Thu, 11 May 2023 04:41:23 +0000</pubDate><category><![CDATA[General]]></category><guid ispermalink="false"> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/?p=15111 </guid><description><![CDATA[<p> My pick for the best ten books on learning how to learn better!</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/10/10-best-learning-books/">Ten Great Books on How to Learn Better</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>; </description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p> What are the best books to read to become a better learner? (Aside from <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/ultralearning/">my book</a> , of course.) I get asked this question a lot, though most of my recent reading lists have been more academic and somewhat removed from immediate applications.</p><p> Today, I&#39;d like to change that and share a list of some of my favorite approachable and actionable books on learning. Here&#39;s ten I highly recommend.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> 1. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-Become-Straight-Student-Unconventional/dp/0767922719">How to Become a Straight-A Student</a> by Cal Newport</h2><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-Become-Straight-Student-Unconventional/dp/0767922719"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/711nrnopRL-664x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15116" width="150" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/711nrnopRL-664x1024.jpg 664w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/711nrnopRL-195x300.jpg 195w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/711nrnopRL-768x1185.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/711nrnopRL-996x1536.jpg 996w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/711nrnopRL-1328x2048.jpg 1328w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/711nrnopRL.jpg 1556w" sizes="(max-width: 664px) 100vw, 664px" /></a></figure></div><p> Although famous for <em>Deep Work</em> , Cal&#39;s early books were aimed at students (that&#39;s how we met). <em>Straight-A</em> is easily the best of Cal&#39;s student-oriented trilogy. Cal derived the content and strategies he recommends from his interviews with relaxed, high-achieving students. He offers concrete, practical advice for getting through college without burning out.</p><p> Other great books by Cal Newport:</p><ul><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-Win-College-Surprising-Countrys/dp/0767917871">How to Win at College</a></li><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-High-School-Superstar-Revolutionary/dp/0767932587">How to Become a High School Superstar</a></li><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Deep-Work-Focused-Success-Distracted/dp/0349413681">Deep Work</a></li></ul><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> 2. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mind-Numbers-Science-Flunked-Algebra/dp/039916524X">A Mind for Numbers</a> by Barbara Oakley</h2><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mind-Numbers-Science-Flunked-Algebra/dp/039916524X"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81mVZQLTTlL-682x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15117" width="150" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81mVZQLTTlL-682x1024.jpg 682w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81mVZQLTTlL-200x300.jpg 200w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81mVZQLTTlL-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81mVZQLTTlL-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81mVZQLTTlL-1365x2048.jpg 1365w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81mVZQLTTlL.jpg 1706w" sizes="(max-width: 682px) 100vw, 682px" /></a></figure></div><p> Barbara Oakley has a number of excellent books on learning. Her free course, <a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/learning-how-to-learn">Learning How to Learn</a> , co-instructed with pioneering cognitive scientist <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terry_Sejnowski">Terrence Sejnowksi</a> , is an excellent resource.</p><p> In <em>A Mind for Numbers</em> , Oakley shares how to tackle difficult quantitative subjects—even if you&#39;ve struggled with math in the past. Oakley speaks from experience, having gone from a self-described “language person” to getting a PhD in engineering.</p><p> Other great books by Barbara Oakley:</p><ul><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Learning-How-Learn-Spending-Studying/dp/0143132547">Learning How to Learn</a></li><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Uncommon-Sense-Teaching-Practical-Insights/dp/0593329732">Uncommon Sense Teaching</a></li></ul><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> 3. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-We-Learn-Brains-Machine/dp/0525559906">How We Learn</a> by Stanislas Dehaene</h2><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-We-Learn-Brains-Machine/dp/0525559906"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/819tBgObpL-668x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15118" width="150" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/819tBgObpL-668x1024.jpg 668w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/819tBgObpL-196x300.jpg 196w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/819tBgObpL-768x1178.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/819tBgObpL-1001x1536.jpg 1001w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/819tBgObpL-1335x2048.jpg 1335w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/819tBgObpL.jpg 1650w" sizes="(max-width: 668px) 100vw, 668px" /></a></figure></div><p> This book is an engaging tour through the science of learning led by one of the world&#39;s leading cognitive neuroscientists. Dehaene elegantly links research on how we learn to the science of how the brain works.</p><p> Other great books by Stanislas Dehaene:</p><ul><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Reading-Brain-New-Science-Read/dp/0143118056">Reading in the Brain</a></li><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Consciousness-Brain-Deciphering-Codes-Thoughts/dp/0143126261">Consciousness and the Brain</a></li></ul><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> 4. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Why-Dont-Students-Like-School/dp/1119715660">Why Don&#39;t Students Like School?</a> by Daniel Willingham</h2><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Why-Dont-Students-Like-School/dp/1119715660"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81dc6sFLBIL-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15119" width="150" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81dc6sFLBIL-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81dc6sFLBIL-200x300.jpg 200w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81dc6sFLBIL-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81dc6sFLBIL-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81dc6sFLBIL-1366x2048.jpg 1366w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/81dc6sFLBIL.jpg 1707w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></a></figure></div><p> Daniel Willingham is one of my favorite educational psychologists who writes for a mass audience. This book argues for the importance of background knowledge, the crucial role attention plays in memory, and how cognition changes as we become more proficient.</p><p> Other great books by Daniel Willingham:</p><ul><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Outsmart-Your-Brain-Learning-Hard/dp/1982167173">Outsmart Your Brain</a></li><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Reading-Mind-Cognitive-Approach-Understanding/dp/1119301378">The Reading Mind</a></li></ul><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> 5. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Make-Stick-Science-Successful-Learning/dp/0674729013">Make it Stick</a> by Peter Brown, Henry Roediger and Mark McDaniel</h2><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-full is-resized"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Make-Stick-Science-Successful-Learning/dp/0674729013"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/51lagMtiKaL.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15120" width="150" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/51lagMtiKaL.jpg 658w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/51lagMtiKaL-197x300.jpg 197w" sizes="(max-width: 658px) 100vw, 658px" /></a></figure></div><p> I confess I haven&#39;t read this book in its entirety. But I have few qualms about recommending it because I&#39;ve greatly benefited from Roediger&#39;s academic work.</p><p> Retrieval practice, spacing, interleaving and other interventions improve learning, but—and this is key—we tend to be unaware of it. There is value in understanding and deploying these studying strategies precisely because they defy our intuitions.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> 6. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Explicit-Teaching-Direct-Instruction-Corwin/dp/1529731607">The Power of Explicit Teaching and Direct Instruction</a> by Greg Ashman</h2><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Explicit-Teaching-Direct-Instruction-Corwin/dp/1529731607"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71b2R8cF6eL-712x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15121" width="150" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71b2R8cF6eL-712x1024.jpg 712w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71b2R8cF6eL-209x300.jpg 209w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71b2R8cF6eL-768x1104.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71b2R8cF6eL.jpg 946w" sizes="(max-width: 712px) 100vw, 712px" /></a></figure></div><p> I&#39;ve shared John Sweller&#39;s <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2022/01/04/cognitive-load-theory/">Cognitive Load Theory</a> on this blog before. Ashman, a disciple of Sweller&#39;s, has written a powerful book explaining why cognitive load is central to learning how to learn.</p><p> Although the primary audience for this book is teachers, I found it very interesting as a learner. While Ashman&#39;s advice—that teachers should fully and thoroughly teach their subjects—don&#39;t sound surprising, it&#39;s an important message because of the alternative theories it rejects. This book is a must-read if you&#39;ve ever struggled with teaching or learning.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> 7. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Peak-Secrets-New-Science-Expertise/dp/0544947223">Peak</a> by Anders Ericsson and Robert Pool</h2><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Peak-Secrets-New-Science-Expertise/dp/0544947223"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61cc4suOpAL-680x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15122" width="150" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61cc4suOpAL-680x1024.jpg 680w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61cc4suOpAL-199x300.jpg 199w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61cc4suOpAL-768x1156.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61cc4suOpAL-1020x1536.jpg 1020w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61cc4suOpAL-1360x2048.jpg 1360w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61cc4suOpAL.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a></figure></div><p> Anders Ericsson&#39;s work is perhaps best known from Malcolm Gladwell&#39;s book <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Outliers-Story-Success-Malcolm-Gladwell/dp/0316017930/ref=sr_1_1?crid=2EEKKWJ7I6H76&amp;keywords=outliers&amp;qid=1683819481&amp;sprefix=outliers%2Caps%2C157&amp;sr=8-1">Outliers</a> , or Geoffrey Colvin&#39;s <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Talent-Overrated-Separates-World-Class-Performers/dp/1591842948/ref=sr_1_1?crid=3UDNNFOGARFER&amp;keywords=talent+is+overrated&amp;qid=1683819492&amp;sprefix=talent+is+overrate%2Caps%2C162&amp;sr=8-1">Talent is Overrated</a> . Deliberate practice has become a buzzword in many circles, but this buzz has also created considerable misconceptions.</p><p> In this book, Ericsson works to set the record straight, arguing both for what deliberate practice is and what it isn&#39;t. Ericsson argues that much of the prowess we see in elite performers is due to huge quantities of this specific kind of practice rather than talent alone.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> 8. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-We-Learn-Move-Revolution/dp/B09KDSQD9Q">How We Learn to Move</a> by Rob Gray</h2><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-We-Learn-Move-Revolution/dp/B09KDSQD9Q"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/51Bs22c3hfL-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15123" width="150" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/51Bs22c3hfL-683x1024.jpg 683w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/51Bs22c3hfL-200x300.jpg 200w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/51Bs22c3hfL-768x1152.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/51Bs22c3hfL.jpg 1000w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></a></figure></div><p> Movement skills have been a gap in my writing on learning. Gray&#39;s book is a highly-readable summary that highlights some interesting research on how we might learn motor skills better.</p><p> Gray argues that a staple of training–repetitive practice in highly constrained conditions to get the “right” movement is not only frequently unhelpful, it isn&#39;t even possible to train a perfectly repetitive movement. Gray argues against the orange training pylon approach to movement skills, instead arguing we can induce new motor patterns better through adjusting constraints that allow for dynamic skills.</p><p> ⠀</p><p> ⠀</p><p> ⠀</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> 9. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-Take-Smart-Notes-Technique/dp/3982438802">How to Take Smart Notes</a> by Sönke Ahrens</h2><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/How-Take-Smart-Notes-Technique/dp/3982438802"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61lo0RTsDL-672x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15124" width="150" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61lo0RTsDL-672x1024.jpg 672w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61lo0RTsDL-197x300.jpg 197w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61lo0RTsDL-768x1170.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/61lo0RTsDL.jpg 893w" sizes="(max-width: 672px) 100vw, 672px" /></a></figure></div><p> Zettelkasten systems, which allow you to organize notes for your studies, research or creative work, are all the rage these days. I&#39;ve <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2022/06/14/building-a-second-brain/">interviewed Tiago Forte for his book</a> , which covers a similar topic.</p><p> Ahrens&#39;s book is a helpful guide to zettelkasten as it&#39;s a bit more nitty-gritty in the implementation details. If you want to know how to organize the things you learn, this book is a great place to start.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> 10. <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Moonwalking-Einstein-Science-Remembering-Everything/dp/0143120530">Moonwalking with Einstein</a> by Joshua Foer</h2><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Moonwalking-Einstein-Science-Remembering-Everything/dp/0143120530"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71Bro5JxeGL-667x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15125" width="150" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71Bro5JxeGL-667x1024.jpg 667w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71Bro5JxeGL-195x300.jpg 195w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71Bro5JxeGL-768x1179.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71Bro5JxeGL-1001x1536.jpg 1001w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71Bro5JxeGL-1334x2048.jpg 1334w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/71Bro5JxeGL.jpg 1649w" sizes="(max-width: 667px) 100vw, 667px" /></a></figure></div><p> Joshua Foer dives into the strange world of super-memorizers. Using mnemonic systems, these people can memorize decks of cards, random digits or entire poems perfectly in around the same time it takes you or I to read them. Foer&#39;s mixture of psychological science and first-person experience was a major inspiration when I wrote <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/ultralearning/">Ultralearning</a> .</p><p> I tend to find mnemonics less helpful for studying than they are often hyped to be. From a practical perspective, I&#39;d recommend <em>Straight-A</em> or <em>Make it Stick</em> above this book. But for a well-written tale to get you inspired to learn better, few books do it better.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Books for Learning Specific Subjects</h2><p> In addition to these more general learning how to learn books, there are a few specific ones I&#39;ve found helpful:</p><ul><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Drawing-Right-Side-Brain-Definitive/dp/1585429201">Drawing on the Right Side of the Brain</a> by Betty Edwards. Setting aside the dubious neuroscience, this book will change how you think about drawing. Highly recommended if you struggle with more than stick figures.</li><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Fluent-Forever-Learn-Language-Forget/dp/0385348118">Fluent Forever</a> by Gabriel Wyner and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Fluent-Months-Anyone-Language-Anywhere/dp/0062282697/ref=sr_1_1?crid=N70U0KOQ5178&amp;keywords=fluent+in+three+months&amp;qid=1683819598&amp;sprefix=fluent+in+three+month%2Caps%2C161&amp;sr=8-1">Fluent in 3 Months</a> by Benny Lewis offer two perspectives on language learning. I&#39;ve long been friends with Benny Lewis, and his efforts inspired my own language-learning journeys. Wyner&#39;s approach is also great.</li><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Learning-Medicine-Evidence-Based-Dr-Peter/dp/0996153306">Learning Medicine: An Evidence-Based Guide</a> . My go-to recommendation for med students.</li><li> <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/Math-Better-Explained-Unlock-Intuition-ebook/dp/B006J5L3VU">Math, Better Explained</a> . My good friend, Kalid Azad, offers a guide to thinking about math in ways that make better sense.</li></ul><p> Of course, you can also check out my book, <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/ultralearning/">Ultralearning</a> , for my thoughts on the subject!</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/10/10-best-learning-books/">Ten Great Books on How to Learn Better</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>;</content:encoded><wfw:commentrss> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/10/10-best-learning-books/feed/</wfw:commentrss><slash:comments> 0</slash:comments></item><item><title> 10 Ways You Can Use ChatGPT to Learn Better</title><link/> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/02/chatgpt-learning-tips/<comments> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/02/chatgpt-learning-tips/#respond</comments><dc:creator><![CDATA[Scott Young]]></dc:creator><pubDate> Wed, 03 May 2023 05:23:17 +0000</pubDate><category><![CDATA[General]]></category><guid ispermalink="false"> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/?p=15093 </guid><description><![CDATA[<p> A compilation of some reader recommendations for how they use ChatGPT to study better.</p><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/02/chatgpt-learning-tips/">10 Ways You Can Use ChatGPT to Learn Better</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>; </description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p> Recently, <a href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/04/03/chatgpt-studying-tips/">I asked readers</a> here to share how they&#39;re using large language models ( <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Large_language_model">LLMs</a> ) like <a href="https://chat.openai.com/chat">ChatGPT</a> to learn and study. Today, I&#39;m rounding up some of those suggestions and trying to synthesize the advice for when (and when not) to use these tools for learning.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Strengths and Weaknesses of LLMs</h2><p> Using applications like ChatGPT requires some care.</p><p> Part of the difficulty is that ChatGPT&#39;s human-like conversation abilities can be deceptive. Feeling like you&#39;re talking to a real person encourages you to rely on conversational expectations that may not hold with a machine.</p><p> For instance, we generally expect that most people do not make up facts. Large language models, however, routinely violate this expectation by providing fluent answers that may be totally wrong. The metacognitive ability to know what you don&#39;t know is underdeveloped in these applications.</p><p> Another expectation we have is that verbal fluency tracks other aspects of intelligence. We expect that someone who can spout lines from Shakespeare, explain quantum computing, and give a proof of the prime number theorem in rhyming verse would also be able to count. Thus, naively treating LLMs like a really smart and knowledgeable person is likely to backfire.</p><p> Those caveats aside, ChatGPT is clearly helpful for a range of tasks. Simon Willison suggests thinking of LLMs as a “ <a href="https://simonwillison.net/2023/Apr/2/calculator-for-words/">calculator for words</a> ”—something that can do useful things with text—rather than as a general-purpose intelligence or smart person.</p><p> I tend to agree. The more we can distinguish the cases where LLMs work well from where they don&#39;t (yet), the more we&#39;ll be able to take advantage of the new capabilities without falling into unexpected traps.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Ten Useful Learning Strategies with ChatGPT</h2><p> After receiving dozens of emails from my audience on how they have been personally using ChatGPT to learn, I&#39;ve compiled some tips with some of the most common suggestions.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 1. Create your own Socratic tutor.</h3><p> By far, the most common use readers reported was using an LLM as a personal tutor.</p><p> Asking ChatGPT to explain tricky concepts, unfamiliar code or problems seems like an area where LLMs might do alright. And the only reasonable substitute (a human expert) is notoriously expensive and in short supply.</p><p> If you do this in conjunction with a class or textbook, the risks of mistakes also seem attenuated since you still have a primary source to compare against. Challenge explanations that don&#39;t jive with what you&#39;ve read in the book rather than taking everything the AI says at face value.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 2. Practice chatting in new languages.</h3><p> The next most common way people used LLMs to learn better was as a language tutor. This seems like a task LLMs are well-equipped for. Whatever their other flaws, they can produce grammatically correct text.</p><p> Many people set up their conversations with ChatGPT so that the AI could go back and forth between the language they are learning and English explanations when they got confused. Likely, those explanations may be imperfect, but human tutors also often give incorrect accounts of the grammar and vocabulary they manage to use proficiently.</p><p> Another use is rewriting texts to be at a more beginner-friendly level of reading comprehension. Graded readers and comprehensive input are great strategies for learning to read in another language. Unfortunately, learner materials are often sparse or uninteresting. You can use an LLM to transform a text you want to read that is written at a fluent native level into something appropriate for your current ability.</p><p> Duolingo seems to be getting in on the <a href="https://blog.duolingo.com/duolingo-max/">LLM game as well</a> . I&#39;ve been harsh on the drag-and-drop style of language learning used in earlier versions, but these new advances may force me to revise my opinion.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 3. Generate summaries of longer texts.</h3><p> Summaries are another area where LLMs seem to excel. Consumer applications already exist for <a href="https://consensus.app/">generating summaries</a> of journal articles or research topics.</p><p> Several readers said they were using these AI tools to provide digests of their substantial reading material, helping them keep atop new developments in their field.</p><p> Good summaries, especially those fine-tuned to your particular needs, might be a good way of navigating the large information loads we often face in knowledge work. You could use it to help prioritize which documents to read in-depth or do a first pass organizing unfamiliar material. </p><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="488" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-Summary-1024x488.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15095" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-Summary-1024x488.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-Summary-300x143.jpg 300w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-Summary-768x366.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-Summary-1536x732.jpg 1536w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-Summary.jpg 1619w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p> It looks like ChatGPT is not able to open links to summarize directly, but it often does a reasonable job hallucinating with famous texts like the one I used above. Until this functionality is standard in the consumer application, it&#39;s better to copy+paste.</p></blockquote><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 4. Dialog with long documents.</h3><p> LLMs also can help you “ask questions” of longer texts. For instance, when reading a scientific paper you could quickly query the sample size or ask for the methodology or results. <a href="https://consensus.app/">Consensus</a> does this while offering references, so the risk of mistakes seems reduced when you can easily double-check the LLM&#39;s work.</p><p> While there are more fanciful usages here, such as people asking ChatGPT to impersonate a given writer and dialog with them, I suspect the ability to ask natural-language questions of documents and receive replies with references is a useful tool for dealing with large texts.</p><p> That said, you must be prepared to fact-check the LLM&#39;s answers. For instance, in the dialog captured below, I asked ChatGPT to list evidence supporting strongly-guided instruction, and it cited a <a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037%2F0003-066X.59.1.14">review article by Mayer</a> . But it falsely claimed Mayer&#39;s work was a meta-analysis, which it isn&#39;t. In fact, the paper isn&#39;t even a comprehensive literature review but simply looks at three prominent cases of the failure of discovery learning. If taken at face value, this response can potentially mislead, but it&#39;s relatively easy to “check” the AI&#39;s work if you know what text it is transforming. </p><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="745" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-text-dialog-1024x745.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-15096" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-text-dialog-1024x745.jpg 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-text-dialog-300x218.jpg 300w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-text-dialog-768x559.jpg 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-text-dialog-1536x1118.jpg 1536w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/GPT-text-dialog.jpg 1542w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 5. Rewrite texts at different levels of explanatory depth.</h3><p> A major difficulty in following expert thinking is that most expert-level text is written for other experts. Concepts are unexplained, context is lacking and jargon abounds. This means that most people must rely on translators, such as general-market nonfiction or science writers, who present what experts think in a more readable format.</p><p> There seem to be two approaches to using AI tools here. One is simply asking an LLM to explain a popular concept in simpler terms, such as: “Explain quantum computing like I&#39;m an eighth-grader.” The other is to provide ChatGPT with a text or explanation and ask the AI to rewrite it in a more digestible manner.</p><p> I tend to think the latter is a little more reliable since you have the source material to compare with rather than taking ChatGPT&#39;s word for it.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 6. Clear up unfamiliar jargon.</h3><p> Several years ago, I remember reading Tyler Cowen&#39;s <a href="http://marginalrevolution.com/">Marginal Revolution blog</a> and being perplexed by his frequent, unexplained use of the term “Straussian” to describe ideas or other thinkers. I Googled for an explanation, but none was forthcoming.</p><p> After a lot of research, I understood the term as meaning, roughly, “closely reading between the lines in prominent thinkers&#39; ideas, looking for what they really meant but couldn&#39;t always express because of prevailing censorship and intellectual orthodoxy.”</p><p> Had ChatGPT existed during my confusion, I could have just gotten this: </p><div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="422" src="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1024x422.png" alt="" class="wp-image-15097" srcset="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1024x422.png 1024w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-300x124.png 300w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-768x316.png 768w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image-1536x632.png 1536w, https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2023/05/image.png 1812w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure></div><p> Many readers found similar benefits in using LLMs to figure out jargon and terms used within a particular community in a way that dictionary definitions often fail to elucidate.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 7. Create study plans and agendas.</h3><p> This usage surprised me, but it showed up enough times among reader replies that I include it here. People seem to like using AI to tell them how and when to learn.</p><p> For instance, some readers asked ChatGPT to break down a complex learning goal and give them a curriculum. Others preferred to go even further, asking for ChatGPT to create a studying schedule for them, given their constraints for the day.</p><p> I probably wouldn&#39;t trust LLMs to give me a well-designed curriculum for a subject. But if I was learning something completely new, it might be a decent starting point. Sometimes the hardest part of approaching a new field is breaking down what appears to be an insurmountable goal. Similarly, sometimes being told when to study can help overcome the inertia of getting started.</p><p> While skill breakdowns might be alright, ChatGPT still struggles with creating reading lists, confabulating books and references. Thus, while it might do well for decomposing an ambiguous learning task, I wouldn&#39;t trust it to give me good resources (yet).</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 8. Provide refreshers on forgotten or infrequently used tools.</h3><p> Programmers were the biggest professional group to reply to my query. I can&#39;t say whether this is because programming is uniquely well-suited to LLMs or because programmers, as a group, are more likely to adopt novel software tools.</p><p> The productivity advantages for programmers seem obvious. I don&#39;t write much code these days, so I haven&#39;t made much use of this well-publicized feature of LLMs. But since a lot of coding is relatively routine, the ability to have a machine create the first draft for an algorithm clearly saves a lot of time.</p><p> While there are cases of people with zero programming knowledge relying on AI output to build applications, I suspect these might be tricky to debug and maintain. In contrast, an expert programmer can override ChatGPT&#39;s output for a language he or she knows particularly well.</p><p> The place LLMs seem to work really well is at the fringes of a programmer&#39;s expertise. Many programmers told me that they found AI helpful in getting starting hints in unfamiliar languages or tools. Their base of programming experience allowed them to make sense of and implement the output, but their unfamiliarity with the underlying language meant the AI saved them a lot of time.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 9. Generate flashcards based on text. (Tentative)</h3><p> Flashcards are a powerful learning tool. They&#39;re also a pain in the butt to make.</p><p> Some readers said they were using ChatGPT to generate flashcards for subjects they&#39;re studying. This seems well within the LLM abilities as a “calculator for words.” Thus, with the correct prompts, you could get fairly good results here—provided you&#39;re inputting the material you wish to see transformed into flashcards and not expecting the LLM to get the facts on its own (see below).</p><p> However, given the difficulty of making “good” flashcards, I wouldn&#39;t enter any into my Anki without reviewing them first. Nonetheless, making flashcards is tedious, so getting a first draft that I later review might speed up the process considerably. The risks seem relatively limited if you confirm the cards&#39; correctness before putting them in your deck.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 10. Use it to organize your notes. (Advanced)</h3><p> As someone who does a lot of research, I often waste a lot of time trying to locate my notes. Robert Martin finds the same problem. Searching via keywords is fraught because sometimes you can&#39;t remember the exact term you used, even if the meaning is roughly the same.</p><p> Martin <a href="https://reasonabledeviations.com/2023/02/05/gpt-for-second-brain/">solves this problem</a> by using the embedding feature of LLMs. While not strictly ChatGPT, this tool from the same family of natural language processing techniques allows you to find semantically-related notes rather than exact keyword matches.</p><p> Personalized LLMs that live on your hard drive and access your existing data may be a valuable application. I&#39;d love to be able to search things I know I&#39;ve seen but can&#39;t quite recall where.</p><h2 class="wp-block-heading"> Some Things NOT To Do</h2><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 1. Don&#39;t expect AI to get facts right.</h3><p> LLMs frequently <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hallucination_(artificial_intelligence)">make stuff up</a> . These hallucinations are problematic if you depend on ChatGPT to give correct answers. The prevalence of these mistakes is difficult to say right now. When Wikipedia was released, for instance, “experts” were in an uproar about how the user-generated nature of the website meant it couldn&#39;t ever be relied upon as a source. Except Wikipedia <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/438900a">actually does fairly well</a> , and some of these knee-jerk reactions were misplaced.</p><p> LLMs haven&#39;t reached Wikipedia&#39;s quality in terms of facts, and we still don&#39;t know much about when they&#39;re likely to get an answer right and when they&#39;re likely to make stuff up. For now, it seems best to use them for situations where the cost of an incorrect answer is minimal, either because you can look it up in a verified source, or because your use of the AI for isn&#39;t factual in nature.</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 2. Don&#39;t expect AI to get citations right.</h3><p> While LLMs sometimes mess up facts, they seem abysmal at getting citations right. They frequently invent authors, papers, studies and research.</p><p> I wouldn&#39;t use a LLM for any research that I needed to cite, and I would always double-check the sources it does provide.</p><p> Similarly, I wouldn&#39;t ask an LLM to give me a reading list or references to specific books or authors (unless, possibly, the authors were quite famous and likely to be well-represented in the data set).</p><h3 class="wp-block-heading"> 3. Don&#39;t expect AI to get the math right.</h3><p> I believe it&#39;s a mistake to attribute general intelligence to LLMs based on their ability to do many tasks at a human level or beyond. As with chess bots and image classifiers, the technology behind LLMs is extremely narrow compared to what we would expect of a human who scored similarly on verbal tests.</p><p> One finding from psychology is that much of reasoning is performed by different subsystems in the brain than those devoted to language. <a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2301.06627?utm_source=substack&amp;utm_medium=email">This paper</a> argues that LLMs seem to match the neurological evidence from double-dissociation studies: you can have fluent verbal abilities with seriously impaired reasoning and vice versa.</p><p> As such, LLMs are really bad at math. And not just higher-level math that humans struggle with. LLMs often fail at <a href="https://garymarcus.substack.com/p/large-language-models-like-chatgpt">basic counting tasks</a> . Thus I suspect LLMs would be uniquely bad at a task like providing practice problems for a math class and grading the answers. ChatGPT might be able to explain a math concept well, but be unreliable at actually using it.</p><blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p> Have you used ChatGPT or other AI tools to further your learning? Share your own observations and suggestions in the comments below!</p></blockquote><p> The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/02/chatgpt-learning-tips/">10 Ways You Can Use ChatGPT to Learn Better</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog">Scott H Young</a> .</p> ]]>;</content:encoded><wfw:commentrss> https://www.scotthyoung.com/blog/2023/05/02/chatgpt-learning-tips/feed/</wfw:commentrss><slash:comments> 0</slash:comments></item></channel></rss>